Welcome back.
欢迎回来
So, in this section we're going to be talking a little more
在这部分 我们将更深入讲解一下权重
about what's going on, a little more theory, a little less project based.
更注重理论 而不太针对某个具体项目
And it's really just about trying to understand what are these weights doing?
主要是要理解 这些权重起了什么作用
What can I attach my mind to when I'm thinking about a neural net training
在我们思考神经网络训练时 应该考虑哪些方面
that's going to be able to help me debug it, help me be able to find better
帮助我们来进行调试 找到更有效的信号
signal and cut out better noise and just have a better framework to work from.
更好地消除噪音 搭建更好的网络框架
To think about things like that.
来思考这些问题
So things that we know, so we're taking this 1 that represents X1, right?
已知 我们用这个 1 代表 excellent
And we're summing it into layer_1 and we're making a prediction.
将这些值相加 得到 layer_1 来进行预测
Now there's an interesting phenomenon that happens when,
这里 有一个有趣的现象
especially when you have linear layers right here.
特别是当存在线性层时
And I talked about this before
我之前的课程很简短地提到过
very briefly when I was saying that we wanted to have a linear layer here and
当时我说 这里需要一个线性层
I said I would talk about it later, and now's the time.
后面课程会再详谈 现在就要详细讲讲这一点了
When we have a linear layer like this, it's making a prediction.
当我们有这样的线性层时 它在进行预测
What's really happening is these four, in this case or
真正发生的是 这 4 个权重（如这个例子中）
more, however many you decide it to be, weights are feature detectors.
或者你自己定有多少个权重 作为特征检测器
What they're doing is, they're trying to detect a certain state in this neuron,
它们所做的就是 检测神经元的一个特定状态
or this neuron, or this neuron.
或者这个神经元 这个神经元
Right, and so if this is like a big negative number,
如果是一个很大的负数
this is looking for this to be a big negative number.
这个应该是大的负数
But if this is zero or if this is a positive number,
但如果这是零 或正数
it's going to have the opposite effect, right?
就会产生相反的效果 对吧？
So these are looking for a certain set of states, it's looking for 0.5, 0.9,
所以 这里在寻找一组特定的值 例如 0.5、0.9、
1 and negative 2, right?
1 和 -2 对吧？
So there are certain hidden layers that cause this to output a high number and
所以 某些隐藏层会使其输出一个较高的预测值
a certain hidden layers that cause this to output a low number.
某些隐藏层会输出一个较低的预测值
And it's just weighted sum, it's actually pretty simple, right?
这只是一个加权求和 很简单 对吧？
If these are positive in all the same times or
如果所有值都为正
all the same ways that these weights are positive, this puts a lot.
这些权重也都为正 结果就很大
But if this is positive and this is negative and this is positive.
但如果这个为正 这个为负 这个为正
Positive, and this is negative.
这个为负
And this is positive, and this is negative.
这个为正 这个为负
Then this ends up being a really really low number, right?
就会得到一个很小的数字 对吧？
So, when these have the same polarity, and
所以 当它们具有相同的正负性
have high values in all the same places, this makes a high prediction.
并且都有很大的值时 最终的预测值就会很大
So what does that mean for all this stuff back here?
那么这些究竟意味着什么呢？
Well, horrible and terrible,
horrible 和 terrible
when we think about what commonly happens in our data set.
当我们思考数据集里的常见现象时
They're associated with negativity, right?
这些词都与“负面”相关联的 对吧？
Excellent, and fantastic, if that was another word up here,
而 excellent 和 fantastic（这是另一个词）
are constantly trying to predict this one.
这些词往往会预测出这一结果（positive）
They're trying to relate to this vector in a certain way, right?
它们都试着以某种方式与这个向量关联
So what's interesting is that if these words are being trained,
有趣的是 如果这些词被训练了
which they're just rows in the matrix, right?
它们只是矩阵中的行 对吧？
They're being trained to manipulate this in the same way,
同样的 它们被训练成能够通过操纵这些值
to create a high value or a low value.
得到一个较高或较低的预测值
What does it mean when we've learned here.
那么 这一训练过程中 究竟学到了什么呢？
We backup the gradients and
我们对梯度做反向传播
we update these to both exhibit the same phenomenon.
更新这些值 使它们都能体现这一相同的预测结果
Horrible and terrible are both supposed to affect this node in the same way.
horrible 和 terrible 都会以同样的方式影响这个值
And as we're updating these weights to cause them to do that, what happens?
那么当我们更新权重 使它们这么做时 发生了什么？
Their weights become similar, why?
它们的权重变得越来越接近 为什么？
Because both of them have the same goal, right?
因为它们都有相同的目标 对吧？
So, if this one predicts positively, this thing's going to go no, no, no.
比如 如果 horrible 给出正面的预测结果 这里会说不不不
Update your weights, mister horrible vector, and
horrible 向量先生 请更新您的权重
be a little more like this, because this is what causes me to predict negative.
请更像这个一些 因为这才会让我给出负面的结果预测
That's what that propagation is all about, it's about this node being able
这就是传播的本质所在 它就是要
to tell these weights how to be better, how to be more accurate, right?
让节点告诉各权重值 如何给出更好、更准确的预测
And because it's sending the same signal, horrible and terrible, right?
因为 horrible 和 terrible 传递的是同样的信号
Be negative, right?
也就是负面 对吧？
They end up congregating together, and it's really quite cool.
这两个值最终会集合成一块 这还挺酷的
So check this out.
那么 看看这个
So we've got kind of a heuristic for
我们在探索
seeing how similar the different vectors are for each word, and
看看这些单词的向量有多相似
now we can go through and we can say, okay, show me the vectors.
现在我们可以搜索说：展示与 excellent
The words that have the most similar vector to excellent.
最相似的向量词
I'm just using a simple .product.
我只是用了一个简单的点乘法
Excellent, perfect, amazing, today, wonderful, fun, great, best, and
Excellent、perfect、amazing、today、wonderful、fun、great、best
this is on a trained neural net.
这些都是训练过的神经网络上的词
Look at that!
看一看
After we trained, because these words, excellent, perfect, amazing, all were
经过训练之后 由于这些词 excellent、perfect、amazing
supposed to create the same effect or very similar effect on the output.
都会对最终的输出产生相似的影响
They were given similar weights.
它们的权重都很相似
Inversely, if we say the opposite, if we say terrible.
相反 如果我们搜索表示负面的词 比如 terrible
Worst, awful, waste, poor, terrible, dull, poorly, disappointment, fail,
会出现 Worst、awful、waste、poor、terrible、dull、poorly、disappointment、fail
disappointing, boring, unfortunate.
disappointing、boring、unfortunate
I mean, it just goes on, and on, and on.
非常非常多
This is actually an even better filter than out original counts.
这实际上是比原来的计数法更好用的一个过滤器
I mean, our counts had these weird names in them,
之前的计数法中会出现一些奇怪的名字
and they just had a noise, but this is awesome.
还有一些噪音 但这个效果非常棒
It's clear, it's evident that the network has figured out
很显然 网络已经明白了
that these words are related, right?
这些词是相互关联的 对吧？
These words are both trying to create the same effect on the output data,
这些词都会对输出数据产生相同的影响
right?
对吧？
Now to be clear, we can't over state this.
不过要明确一点 我们也不能夸大它
It doesn't know that these have the same meaning generally.
网络并不知道 这些词普遍具有相同的含义
All it knows is that they have the same meaning in the context
它只知道 在这个输出神经元的语境下 这些词具有
of this one output neuron, because it's the only output neuron there.
相同的意义 因为这里只有一个输出神经元
They exist to create the same effect as this neuron.
它们的存在只是能产生与这个神经元相同的影响
Now we had a bunch of different neurons that were pushing it in one way or
我们可能有一堆不同的神经元 将词汇推向一边或
another to be the same or
另一边
different in a bunch of different ways, this could get a lot more complicated.
或以很多不同的方式产生不同 问题可以变得非常复杂
But basically it grouped words by sentiment, right?
但基本来说 它是按照情感属性将单词进行分组 对吧？
It said hey,
它说
all your negative words have a really similar vector coming out of you and
所有表示负面的词汇都有非常相似的向量
all your positive words have a really similar vector coming out of you.
所有表示正面的词汇也有非常相似的向量
And that's a really powerful intuition,
这是非常强大的直觉
because that means you can look at a neural net like this and you can say,
因为这意味着 当你看到这样一个神经网络 你可以说
hm, okay, we're going to trade it for this.
好的 我们要训练它
So it's probably going to group these vectors like this and these vectors like
你可以将这些词分为一组
this, and you can kind of start to think about what´s going on under the hood and
将这些词分为一组 然后看看 背后究竟发生了什么
how you can, once again, identify signal and noise.
而且 你如何可以识别信号与噪音
Because that´s what framing the problem is really all about.
因为这就是问题设计的核心目标
Now to kind of add a bit of extra kind of jazz to this.
现在 我再给大家来点有意思的
What I like to do is something that's called tf–idf.
我喜欢用一个叫作 tf–idf 的工具
So tf–idf, what it does is it takes a high dimensional vector, and
tf–idf 的作用是取一个高维向量
in our case, high dimensions might just be four, right?
在我们的例子中 高维只有 4 维
And it clusters them into two dimensions, or
它将它们分为两个维度
some other, with how many you pick, so we can plot them on an X Y graph and
或你指定的其他维度 然后可以将它们绘制在 X Y 图上
see how they're naturally clustered in a higher dimension.
看它们如何在更高维度图中自然聚集
And the cool thing is that we can do that here.
很酷的一点就是 我们现在就可以做
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to cluster them,
我要做的就是 将它们分为集群
but then I'm also going to say hey, the words that are our
然后说 那些正负比为正的词
ratio instead of really positive I'm going to make them green, and
我要将它们显示为绿色
the ones that were really negative I'm going to to make them black.
那些正负比为负的词 我要将它们显示为黑色
And so, in theory because all these vectors are really similar,
那么 理论上来说 因为这些向量都非常类似
it should cluster, or it should show how they're clustered already.
它们应该会聚集在一起 图上会显示它们已经聚在一起了
And look at that.
看看
So it's, I mean there's a couple that are scattered in between but,
虽然中间有一些掺杂在一起
the neural net that has clearly separated those.
但神经网络已经清楚地将这些分隔开了
There's this big long negative cluster, big long negative cluster.
这里有一条长长的负面词集群
And then these really nice positive clusters.
然后这些都是非常不错的正面词集群
Let's take a look.
来看看
So I think we can add labels here.
我来试着让它显示标签
I left them in, that was kind of messy.
我让标签显示出来了 看起来有点凌乱
Check this out.
我们来看看
So we click that real zoom, you can kind of look in.
我放大一点 你可以看得更清楚一些
Wow, interesting.
哇塞 有意思
So unconvincing, dimensional, lousy.
我看到了 unconvincing、dimensional、lousy
Look at this.
看看这个
Extraordinary, lovable, provoking, award, touched.
Extraordinary、lovable、provoking、award、touched
It's beautiful, it's awesome.
很美观 很棒
So we can kind of look around.
我们可以到处看看
So this, maybe we'll call this a vector space.
这个 我们可以称这个为向量空间
And actually you see the ones that
事实上
are kind of agnostic are like the ones with those names.
这里面还有一些无关的东西 像这些名称
So this is kind of a little bit of a noisier one.
所以这是一条噪音
It's like Dan right there.
像这里的 Dan
[LAUGH] But still it did a really good job of
[笑] 但总体而言 它已经做得很棒了
clustering vectors by sentiment automatically, right?
按情感属性自动对向量进行聚类 对吧？
I guess I told it to do this because I gave it training data to allow it to do
我刚刚说了 它之所以能做这一分类 是因为我用训练数据训练它
this.
让它这么做
But all it was trying to do is predict accurately, but implicitly while
但它所做的 只是尝试做出准确的预测
it was trying to predict accurately, it had to group these words to have
但是隐含其中的是 为了做出准确的预测 它必须要先将这些词分类
similar different vectors so that it can classify them in aggregate when they're
将类似的向量分到一起 从而当求和时
all summed together as being more positive or more negative.
所有正面或负面的值相加就会更大
And that's what the neural network did.
这就是神经网络所做的
And it's really cool to kind of see it kind of behave this way.
它表现效果非常炫酷
And so I guess to close, this is what neural nets are all about.
总结来说 这就是神经网络的核心所在
This is what framing the problem's all about.
也是问题构建的核心所在
It's about understanding what's going on under the hood so
就是要理解它背后发生的活动
you can reduce the noise as much as possible.
尽可能减少噪音
Increase the signal as much as possible so
尽可能放大信号
that it can find the structure that you're interested in it finding.
以找到你想要找的结构
We didn't tell it that lovable and
我们没告诉它 lovable 和
extraordinary were similar terms in this context.
extraordinary 这两个词在这一语境下是非常相似的
All we said was, hey, all these reviews are positive,
我们告诉它的信息只有：所有这些评论都是正面的
all these reviews are negative, figure it out.
所有这些都是负面的 找出它们的规律吧
And it figured out which terms were similar, which terms were different.
然后它就搞清楚了 哪些词是相似的 哪些是不同的
It was able to do that to make accurate predictions.
它通过这种方式做出了准确了预测
So I hope you've enjoyed this segment.
那么 希望你在这部分有所收获
So we'll see you soon and continue to enjoy your course.
待会见 享受学习吧